Rong Zhuang

China Town, Chicago, IL 60616 Phone: (312) 478-6579 Email: jojozhuang@gmail.com

Personal website: http://jojozhuang.github.io/

Objective

Fresh *Master graduate* major in Computer Science(GPA 3.9) with 2 years part-time working experience(Web+Mobile) in DePaul University. Seeking for a full-time Software Development position starting from July 2016.

Professional Summary

12 years of software development experience, with 3 years in product and project maintenance. Familiar with software development life cycle(SDLC), strong passion in new technologies, good at *quick prototyping*. A collaborative team player with excellent communication and documentation skills. Proficient in both SAP(5 years) and Microsoft .NET(7 years) platform. 6 years of web application development, 1 year of iOS, Android and hybrid mobile app development.

Skills

Microsoft: C#/ASP.NET MVC/WinForm(Proficient), SQL Server/IIS(Familiar), Azure(Working experience)

• Front-End jQuery/Node.Js(Proficient), Html5/Bootstrap/jQuery/Facebook React(Familiar)

Mobile: iOS/Android(Familiar), Cordova/Xamarin(Working experience)

Big Data: Hadoop/MapReduce/Hive/Pig/EC2/Python/IPython Notebook(Working experience)
SAP: ABAP/WebDynpro/SAP GUI (Proficient), Entry Page/BOBJ Dashboard(Familiar)

Java & DB: Java/Servlet/JSP(Familiar), PL/SQL(Familiar)

Experience

Senior Developer(Part Time)

DePaul University

Sep 2014 – Present

- Quickly designed and built 3 prototypes with Html5, PhoneGap and Xamarin for 5 weeks to analyze cross-platform mobile development solutions. Created the investigation document for director to make decision.
- Designed and developed an online video sharing application with Facebook React and ASP.NET Web API.
- Implemented online course player with two different technologies, SignalR in ASP.NET and Socket.IO in Node.js.

Senior Developer/Architect

SAP Labs China

Oct 2009 - Aug 2014

- Led team(8 members) to finish development for China localization of SAP GTS, project ran in lean/scrum model.
- Collected requirements and finalized designs by negotiating with customers, partners and product owner.
- Created a new web portal for GTS Customs Management with SAP Entry Page.
- Released more than 60 notes for bugs fixing and function enhancement.
- Independently developed a complicate SAP Process Control Dashboard(contains 8 charts) with BOBJ Xcelsius.

Senior Software Engineer

Infosys Technologies China

Nov 2007 - Sep 2009

- Developed modules in Microsoft MSSolve project which is run in scrum model with WPF & WCF.
- Led team(3 members) to develop a newsletter subscription web application with ASP.NET, finished all development and testing tasks three weeks earlier than planned.
- Smoothly took over tough maintenance tasks from India colleagues of Syngenta support team within 2 months.

Software Engineer

Amano Software Engineering Co., Ltd

Oct 2006 - Nov 2007

- Improved quality and performance of Amano Attendance System by refining the .NET source codes.
- Investigated and solved the compatible issues in the new environment (OS, Web Browser, .NET Framework etc.).

Software Engineer

HuaZhong Computer Software Engineering Co., Ltd

July 2004 - Jul 2006

- Worked on the most complex module(a screen with 8 tab pages, about 400 controls and 28,000 lines code) of a windows desktop application, refactored it from VB6.0 to C#.
- Participated in several out-sourcing projects by using ASP, javascript, VBscript, C#, Java and created highperformance reports with PL/SQL and ActiveReport.

Education

M.S: Computer Science (Full Scholarship, GPA: 3.9)

Sep 2014 – June 2016

DePaul University - Chicago, IL, US

Coursework: Mining Big Data, Intelligent Information Retrieval, iOS Dev, Android Dev, OO programming, etc.

B.S: Computer Science and Technology

Sep 2000 – June 2004

East China University of Science & Technology - Shanghai, China